<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Video Draft on David&#39;s Blogs</title>
        <link>https://blog.yorforger.cc/categories/video-draft/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Video Draft on David&#39;s Blogs</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 21:30:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.yorforger.cc/categories/video-draft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Compiled and Interpreted Languages - Video Draft</title>
        <link>https://blog.yorforger.cc/p/compiled-and-interpreted-languages-video-draft/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 21:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.yorforger.cc/p/compiled-and-interpreted-languages-video-draft/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-computers-only-know-binary-code&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#1-computers-only-know-binary-code&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    1. Computers only know binary code
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two ways to convert human-readable code to binary code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compilation:&lt;/strong&gt; The code is converted to binary code before it is executed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interpretation:&lt;/strong&gt; The code is converted to binary code as it is executed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-a-compiled-binary-code-cannot-be-run-on-a-different-os&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#why-a-compiled-binary-code-cannot-be-run-on-a-different-os&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    Why a compiled binary code cannot be run on a different OS?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;isa-instruction-set-architecture&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#isa-instruction-set-architecture&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    ISA (Instruction Set Architecture)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISA:&lt;/strong&gt; The CPU has a set of predefined actions called the instruction set or ISA (instruction set architecture). &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://arc.net/l/quote/ildxcafd&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popular ISAs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x86: Intel and AMD processors, high performance.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not the case in nowadays, ARM is also used in high-performance devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One reason os that some powerful GPUs, such as NVIDIA works better with x86 processors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARM: Often used in the devices with small battery, such as smartphones, embedded systems, such as snapdragon, and Apple&amp;rsquo;s A-series chips, and Raspberry Pi, STM32. M-series chips.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIPS: used in switches and routers, and some embedded systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;os-operating-system&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#os-operating-system&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    OS (Operating System)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Different OSs have different system calls. We use standard libraries to make system calls, such as &lt;code&gt;printf&lt;/code&gt; in C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cross-compilation&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#cross-compilation&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    Cross-compilation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cross-compilation is the process of compiling code for a platform different from the one on which the compiler is running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-cross-compilation&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#why-cross-compilation&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    Why cross-compilation?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some machines are not powerful enough to compile the code. For example, compiling code for a micro-controller on a Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-cross-compile&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#how-to-cross-compile&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    How to cross-compile?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cross-platform&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#cross-platform&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    Cross platform
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Java - Write once, run anywhere. Benefits from the JVM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python - Benefits from the Python interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C, C++ - Cross-compile the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years, the typical answer to the &amp;ldquo;ARM CPU vs. x86?&amp;rdquo; question was that x86es are better suited to desktop and high-performance computing, while ARM chips were better suited for mobile devices. That perception changed when Apple released its ARM-based M1 chips in 2020, followed by the powerful M2 series in 2022. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://arc.net/l/quote/pmsoload&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;x86 processors typically operate independently of peripheral components, such as RAM and GPUs. But ARM processors were designed to package these additional components into a central unit. That&amp;rsquo;s why ARM processors operate as part of a System on Chip (SOC). &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://arc.net/l/quote/zvffhkyc&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you communicate with GPUs, you typically use graphics libraries such as OpenGL, Vulkan, or DirectX. The company that sold you the &lt;strong&gt;graphics card&lt;/strong&gt; also provides a graphics driver that translates commands from these graphics libraries into instructions that the GPU can understand. The instructions that your graphics driver generate are in a proprietary protocol known only to a few wizards at NVIDIA and AMD who actually understand how GPUs work on a low level. Us mere mortals don&amp;rsquo;t get to look under the hood at these instructions.
Interestingly, many modern CPUs operate the same way. They take your x86 code and internally translate it into something better, faster, and chip specific. Adopted from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://arc.net/l/quote/zvuupchl&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
